<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2023 jcupitt -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.libvips.nip4</id>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/jcupitt/nip4</url>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <name>nip4</name>
  <summary>Image processing spreadsheet</summary>
  <developer_name>jcupitt</developer_name>

  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>

  <recommends>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </recommends>

  <description>
    <p>
*This is a first alpha release for testing this new
version of nip. Don't use it for anything serious!*

nip4 is a GUI for the libvips image processing library. It's a little
like a spreadsheet: you create a set of formula connecting your objects
together, and on a change nip2 will recalculate. This makes it convenient
for developing image processing systems since you can watch pixels change
as you adjust your equations.

Because nip4 uses libvips as the image processing engine it can handle very
large images and only needs a little memory. It scales to fairly complex
workflows: I've used it to develop systems with more than 10,000 cells,
analyzing images of many tens of gigabytes.

It has a batch mode, so you can run any image processing system you develop
from the command-line and without a GUI.

    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.libvips.nip4.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>

    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jcupitt/nip4/master/images/shot1.png</image>
      <caption>A new interface design</caption>
    </screenshot>

    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jcupitt/nip4/master/images/shot2.png</image>
      <caption>Workspaces from older versions load correctly</caption>
    </screenshot>

  </screenshots>

  <releases>

    <release version="9.0.11" date="2025-07-21">
      <description>
        <p>

		This version has a rewritten tilecache which should be o
		dramatically faster in many cases. Flicker on updates should
		also be gone. Plus many small fixes, see the CHANGELOG.

        </p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="9.0.10" date="2025-06-22">
      <description>
        <p>

		This version adds better OME-TIFF handling (along with other
		image display improvements), better menu state initialisation,
		and more view properties are shared with thumbnails. It adds
		"Merge column" and "Merge tab" submenus. Region manipulation
		during recomputation is now much more responsive.

        </p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="9.0.9" date="2025-05-31">
      <description>
        <p>

          Better select modifier handling, added horizontal and vertical
          guides, regions snap to gudes, better menu homing, better
          anitialias on zoom out, added a region context menu.

        </p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="9.0.5" date="2025-03-20">
      <description>
        <p>
          Image windows are faster and more reliable, matrix recalculation
          is more robust, fixed a crash after row drag, fixed replace from
          file in sub-rows, started revising menus.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="9.0.4" date="2025-03-20">
      <description>
        <p>
          Image windows are faster and more reliable, workspace load is more
          robust, fixed a bug in save-as, fixed a bug in graph export.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="9.0.2" date="2025-03-11">
      <description>
        <p>
          Image windows are faster and more reliable, file chooser widgets
          support drag and drop, long formula truncate correctly.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="9.0.1" date="2025-02-24">
      <description>
        <p>
          First test release we distribute.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="9.0.0-11" date="2025-02-18">
      <description>
        <p>
          First test release.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1" date="2024-02-04">
      <description>
        <p>
          Project start.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>

  </releases>

</component>
